don't mind me
i've just got a couple of withers to
take care of
now i found the one behind me
but there's a wither on the loose
and i have no idea where it is
this is the aftermath of the barge quest
and i kinda can't leave these guys just
standing around
so we're gonna try and take care of them
the old-fashioned way
cheese in it
so we're gonna do this by flying in the
air
and whacking him with my axe we're gonna
find out how difficult this really is
they had such a hard time doing this it
took them like half an hour
in fact i can probably get a good time
of this
um
i think he's vanished
this wither has legitimately vanished if
it gets too high it vanishes
what on earth
he i
i'm gonna have to just guess where it is
can't beat them
i can't beat them
and what is going on here flying you
know i should have definitely tested the
wither fight thing
before i sent four people to do this
i've been at this for 20 minutes now i
haven't killed one of them mainly
because as soon as it hits a certain
height at this at the top
it vanishes and i can't see it
so
i don't know what to do so my new tactic
is to get them to half health on the
ground
and then
they become immune to
projectiles i believe
now i need to take it in the air and
i've got to kill them before they get to
the top and vanish on me
one more come on one more
there we go
oh my goodness
so
i think we can pretty easily say that
the wither fight
kind of sucks the only time i've ever
killed another wither i did it in the
air
and that fight kind of sucked too
i think withers suck
they they they're just not good
hey
hey skydrop oh
man okay so total time to kill two
withers
was
minutes
full minutes nearly an hour
so
i guess i will be the first to apologize
for the end of the barge quest i in
hindsight should have maybe only made
one wither and made them fight for it
i did not expect
that one wither would be so difficult to
kill and so boring as well it just
wasn't a fun fight in fact most of the
time i was just sighing and hitting it
okay right
i'm kind of glad i took care of that
because there's a lot of
industrial buildings around here and the
wither was getting
incredibly close that could have caused
some major destruction so it's a good
job we took care of that and now we can
go back to the base right we got that
out of the way now there's some
improvements to the mansion that i've
been looking at doing
and one of them is continuing to mine
this out i have actually done a little
bit of progress but also i really really
would like to expand
my villager hall this is where i do the
majority of my trading and work and
grinding for resources
but actually i need to expand it because
i don't have enough of them to make it
as efficient as possible so i'd like to
kind of bring in some more but if you
remember
back at the start of the season
i made the very real claim that
villagers are the worst and it's true
but i'd like to get them some grain haha
green
i would like to get them some bread and
get me some more villagers so that i can
trade with them
so we'll craft ourselves up some
bread
so
some
grain
grain who's this grain character i think
i found him yep
over the years
autocorrect has not been kind to my name
green and the majority of the mistakes
come in the form of
grain so i decided it's time to just
lean into it
and be done with it and this is what we
got grain himself
the bread green that's really really
cute
i'm gonna leave my bread as grain
forever but also
i decided to put it on a t-shirt it's on
a t-shirt
and it's in my brand new merch store and
there's a link in the description to
check it out look at this i got grain
t-shirts who is this green character
sorry the way the way that that just
flies in like that hold on look
well i got green t-shirts and i also got
something very dear to my heart pesky
bird t-shirts i know it's been nearly a
year since we brought in professor beak
the original pb pesky bird but we
finally got a design on a t-shirt pesky
bird t-shirt and also on a hat i'm
probably a little bit more excited for
the hat but i really really am proud of
these designs and if you order before
december the 6th it is guaranteed
shipping before christmas so it is a
very limited time offer to get your
hands on one of these breads
and it's also limited time for a pesky
bird t-shirt so click the link in the
description if you'd like to check it
out i'm very proud of these t-shirts and
i can't wait to get my hands on them
myself i feel like i need to take grain
on a little adventure over here oh wait
that's totally right i'm go i've got to
feed grain to the to these guys
here you go enjoy the grain did you guys
pick them up yes yes yes yes yes yes i
did yes yes yes what is going on
what is happening
just like me they can't get enough grain
you know it used to kind of annoy me the
amount of times i get called grain or
grind or whatever it is everyone's
calling me but now i'm just gonna lean
into it it's just grain for everyone now
i remember why i don't do this
because it never works properly okay
i think we may have to ditch this idea
we're gonna save our grain for villagers
who appreciate it
and i think i think this place
is really unfit for purpose look at it
it's a mess
i feel like i should transfer these guys
into a machine that works a little bit
better maybe even inside
the main mansion itself there's a few
things that i wanted to add up there
but i think this thing this machine is
way past its expiration date but i'm not
sure i can stomach moving villages again
i'm gonna have to psych myself up for
that however i did actually receive a
message from hypno saying that he wanted
to have a word about my proposal
on his shop now that doesn't sound like
a no does it
so he hasn't taken the diamonds so let's
ask him what's going on
hey how's it going green yeah not bad i
don't think we've ever really like
chatted this season so hi how are you
doing yeah i don't think we have either
i'm doing well how are you i'm good so
you saw my my offer i take it yeah i saw
the offer and
i thought it was a little low just a
little bit oh okay okay okay okay fair
enough fair enough hold on let me let me
grab some diamonds now you just uh
you tell me when
when when you want when you want to stop
oh i can just tell you when to stop huh
okay
uh
stop we'll we'll call it there okay
we'll call it there i'll throw in some
grain as well
oh so great
look at that okay cool cool cool uh so
yeah obviously like i would love to
expand the barge but i don't want to i
don't want to force any sale or anything
do you want me if you're going to move
this like i don't want to sell tridents
that's your thing i can move this shop
if you want me to or i mean i could move
it you can move it i mean i i don't want
it taken down for sure but yeah we can
relocate it that's not a big deal okay
cool sweet well thank you for taking my
offer and uh
i mean you could have
you know what take some more diamonds
i was i was prepared to go that far whoa
whoa
how many is this anyway oh okay
all right cheers thank you very much
hypno that's that's gonna be brilliant i
can expand the barge
quite far
well that is amazing
we have got ourselves a big old chunk of
land so i'm pretty sure we can safely
say
that we can edit
up to probably up to here i'm sure i can
work out a system to engulf this pathway
and that would mean that i can settle
myself around here with the barge if we
take a look from above what does this
look like
well it's not double the size and
there's some big old trees in the way
however
there is a big option to expand over
here
and i also think it's time we actually
cashed out
on the barge quest diamonds i haven't
actually done anything with these how
often do you see an inventory full of
diamonds like that not very often
not very often at all stacks and stacks
and stacks of diamonds
so i've been massively thinking what to
do up here and i've decided that i'm
going to sell things by the box and one
of the first things that i want to do
here is die boxes i am going to start
encroaching on other people's business
so i'm gonna need to make a flower farm
but before we go and do another farm and
start working on the barge a bit more
there's a there's something i've been
meaning to do
now you remember in the last mycelium
headquarters meeting we all decided to
go on the attack and each and every one
of us has a different idea on how to
show hep who's boss and mine is
something that i've been looking at
doing for quite some time i mean they've
done the majority of the work for me
let's play a little game called spot the
difference so
corporate wants you to find the
difference between these two images
image a
and image b
they're the same image
and that's it
or at least they will be the same image
when i'm through with it
so what we're gonna do
for our attack is we're going to turn
hep hq into the llama that it always has
been all we got to do is add a little
schnut right here the difficulty here of
course is that it may end up looking
cuter than it did before so season six
my base got called a water filter season
seven their base gets called a llama
so let's go and gather some materials
and let's let's make a llama so make a
llama out of this base
[Music]
look at that
it may seem like this was a lot of
effort it actually took 40 minutes and
for a build that size that's nothing but
here's the thing hep did most of the
work for me
it genuinely looks
so good
as a llama
i love it
it should have just been like this from
the start so i've i've kept kept in all
the the gubbins and stuff i had to
remove like an e or something that's
easy enough to replace afterwards but my
goodness if i had a nickel for every
llama that was built in the shopping
district i'd have two nickels which
isn't a lot but it's weird that it
happened twice
i've always wanted to say that
okay so the mission is accomplished i
can't wait to see what scar's reaction
is to that look if you're gonna build a
base that looks like an animal you're
gonna get it turned into an animal it's
just how hermitcraft works right that's
why you got to build your base as a
giant mushroom castle because it doesn't
look like an animal
at all but there is a very long
railway track
leading straight into the cup what is
going on here i don't want to know no i
don't want to know i don't want to know
i am scared to go in this base because
doc is doing some stuff in here
no i don't want to know no i'm not going
in i don't want to know and actually i
totally forgot something really really
important barge is my favorite shop that
i've ever made on hermitcraft i love it
it's it's been it's grown from a little
a little baby raft into the big boy that
it is today
and i've got a t-shirt that goes with it
so i know i already plugged my t-shirt
and that's really rude of me to plug
again but check it out i also have barge
t-shirts check it out barge the great
green emporium so show your love for the
barge if you want to check it out the
link is in the description and speaking
of shops have you seen what scar is
doing
and also can we take a minute to
appreciate how much bigger the shopping
district has got because we quickly ran
out of space
look at this this is
aqua town or something and he thought he
could get away
with forgetting about my plot
he thought i'd forget
so i put a couple of signs just to
remind him green spot also green spot
i own a random plot remember i i spent
that diamond block very early on in the
season and i claimed a small section to
be very disruptive
in whatever plans he's got so whatever
scar is making here and i have a feeling
it's got to be a big shop right it's
scar he's gonna he's gonna build a big
shop i reckon it's gonna be city we're
gonna make something super disruptive
we're not gonna ruin his build don't get
me wrong but if he's building
skyscrapers we're making a barge scraper
right next to it
so i just thought i'd let you know that
no one has forgotten
or at least i made sure no one has
forgotten that i own a spot there
so
i mentioned earlier that i wanted to
make a dye farm and that means i need to
go and find myself
a flower biome i actually don't know
what they're called are they called
flower bite they're definitely not
called flower biomes the issue is i've
flown around my base many times and
unfortunately
there is no flower biome anywhere near
me so i'm gonna have to do a little bit
of exploring to find one and then of
course i'm gonna have to remember the
way to get back this isn't far from my
base at all what's it called
it's called a flower forest
dude this is exactly what i need and
there are a lot of flowers here i think
i actually saw someone's flower farm
just here
so
i need to i need to remember because the
only flower farm i've ever made
was back in season six and it had a bit
of everything now i i believe if you
bone meal a bit of grass
does it come back with only the same
flowers or is it literally random every
time because i'm seeing a lot of red and
orange tulips but i'm not seeing any
blue or anything so do i need to spread
this out over a wide area yeah look at
this i'm only getting the same flowers i
think it's like chunk specific but i may
be wrong if i go over here in theory
that should be corn flowers and purple
tulips yeah okay right so we need to
pick and choose our spots
wisely i don't know if there's a system
for this but look purple red
white well they give they give white and
then gray
and then blue so if i just make a long
flower farm that should in theory do the
trick in theory i've never i've never
made one of these before and i'm also
not super interested in copying a design
sometimes sometimes in minecraft the
satisfaction comes from knowing that you
made it yourself using your own noggin
so that's what we're going to use we're
going to use our two remaining brain
cells and we are going to figure out how
to make an automatic flower farm i'm
gonna try and work backwards on this one
starting with the collection system
i think this should work
you know what this is too embarrassing
to explain on the spot because i don't
know what i'm doing
let's go into a quick time lapse and
then you can see if you can spot me
struggling
[Music]
well
it works i managed to make a fully
functional oh look he's bringing me a
flower isn't that cute oh he's burning
oh dear
this is what we call a hot delivery
thanks so i'm gonna call this a massive
massive success
so
this is this is the most janky redstone
you've ever seen but it works we got
ourselves a redstone loop
that activates a bunch of bone meal
underneath the ground
where zombies like to spawn
and
it is timed perfectly so it dispenses
releases the water and all gets pushed
as efficiently as possible and from this
we get orange
red
blue
pink
is that white or light gray i always
forget
light gray
and is this also light gray and light
grey so we've got two lots of light gray
and of course white dye from the bone
meal but we've got plenty of we got a
bone farm so white white dye is
definitely not an issue but this is a
really really good start now all the
other colors that we might need such as
uh yellow
we can get through
double flower farms so this gives us the
dyes that we particularly need but guess
what this build took way longer this
puny flower farm took longer than
building the llama
unbelievably i think i'm just gonna hang
out a little bit here and fill up a
couple of shulker boxes full of stuff so
with this complete all there is left to
say is thank you very much for watching
i have run out of time officially i want
to say a huge thank you for listening to
me about my new merch store please check
it out if you haven't already and i also
want to say we got a lot done like we
killed two withers
built a llama a flower farm and we got
some space for the barge like
is this not the most diverse
hermitcraft episode achievement ever i
never thought i would have got what is
going on here
okay this is weird i never thought i
would have built a llama in a flower
farm in the same episode but here we are
episode 55
all done so thank you very much for
watching and i'll see you in the next
one good bye